<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2025-12-19T21:18:31+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Alex Laverty</title><subtitle>The ramblings of a mad man.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Genealogical Report: The Cook (Koch), Coulter, Laverty, and McGree Families of New South Wales</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Cook-Koch-Coulter-Laverty-and-McGree-Families-of-New-South-Wales" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Genealogical Report: The Cook (Koch), Coulter, Laverty, and McGree Families of New South Wales" /><published>2025-12-19T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2025-12-19T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Cook-Koch-Coulter-Laverty-and-McGree-Families-of-New-South-Wales</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Cook-Koch-Coulter-Laverty-and-McGree-Families-of-New-South-Wales"><![CDATA[<h3 id="genealogical-report-the-cook-koch-coulter-laverty-and-mcgree-families-of-new-south-wales"><strong>Genealogical Report: The Cook (Koch), Coulter, Laverty, and McGree Families of New South Wales</strong></h3>

<p>This report details the history of several interconnected families—the Koch (later Cook), Coulter, Laverty, and McGree families—who emigrated from Europe in the mid-19th century and settled in the Mid North Coast region of New South Wales, primarily around the Macleay and Nambucca Rivers, including areas like Stuart’s Point and Taylors Arm.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="early-history-and-immigration-1825---1865"><strong>Early History and Immigration (1825 - 1865)</strong></h4>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>27 May 1825 – Birth of Johann Peter Koch:</strong>
Johann Peter Koch was born in Mannheim, Baden-Württemberg, Germany. His father was Johann Georg Koch.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>c. 1830 – Birth of Anna Katharina Schroder:</strong>
Anna Katharina Schroder was born in Wanstadt, Baden, Germany, to Catherine and Jacob Schroeder.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>12 August 1852 – Marriage of Koch and Schroder:</strong>
Johann Peter Koch married Anna Katharina Schroder in Wallstadt, Baden-Württemberg, Germany.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>24 September 1852 – Birth of Son, Franz:</strong>
Their first child, a son named Franz (Frank), was born in Wallstadt, Germany.</p>
  </li>
  <li><strong>29 April 1853 – Arrival in Australia:</strong>
Peter Koch (aged 28), his wife Anna Catherine (aged 23), and their 7-month-old son Franz arrived in Sydney, Australia. The Hamburg Passenger Lists identify them as departing from Wallstadt, with Peter’s occupation listed as <em>Weinbauer</em> (Vinedresser). The official “List of Immigrants” for their ship confirms their names, ages, and religion (Evangelical). The document also notes that Peter’s parents (Georg and Elizabeth) were deceased, as was Anna’s father (Jacob), though her mother was still alive.
    <ul>
      <li><em>Note on ship name:</em> While most documents, including the detailed shipping lists and newspaper arrival notices, name the vessel as the <strong>Triton</strong>, Peter Cook’s later Certificate of Naturalization from 1878 lists the ship as the <strong>“Droden”</strong>. This appears to be a clerical error on the naturalization certificate, as the ‘Triton’ arrival is well-documented.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>30 January 1865 – Arrival of Laverty and Coulter Families:</strong>
The ship <strong>“Saint Hilda”</strong> arrived in Australia carrying assisted immigrant passengers. Among them were:
    <ul>
      <li><strong>The Laverty Family:</strong> Michael Laverty (30, Labourer) and his wife Sarah (28) from County Monaghan, Ireland, with their children Michael (infant, died on the voyage), Dennis (5), Catherine (3), and Sarah (infant).</li>
      <li><strong>William James Coulter (21, Labourer):</strong> From Dromore, County Tyrone, Ireland.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h4 id="settlement-and-second-generation-1864---1900"><strong>Settlement and Second Generation (1864 - 1900)</strong></h4>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>15 July 1864 – Birth of Alfred Henry Cook:</strong>
Alfred Henry Cook was born in Picton, NSW, to Peter and Anna Catherine Cook. He was the seventh of their twelve children and the last to be born in Picton before the family relocated to the Macleay River district.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>6 March 1875 – Birth of Jessie Elvina Coulter:</strong>
Jessie Elvina Coulter was born to William James Coulter and Emily Gill.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>24 August 1878 – Naturalization of Peter Cook:</strong>
Peter Cook, now residing in the Macleay River district and working as a farmer, was officially naturalized as a British subject in the Colony of New South Wales. The certificate notes he had been a resident for 25 years.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>26 June 1891 – Elopement and Marriage of Alfred Cook and Jessie Coulter:</strong>
Alfred Henry Cook and Jessie Elvina Coulter married in Kempsey. A newspaper article titled “An Elopement Case” details the events leading up to their marriage. Jessie, being under 21, ran away with Alfred because her parents did not approve of the match. She admitted to stealing money from her mother to pay for their travel to Port Macquarie. Alfred was charged and committed to trial after Jessie’s father refused the Police Magistrate’s suggestion to withdraw the charge and allow the young couple to marry. Despite this, they did marry. They would go on to have eleven children, including Ethel Stella (b. 1892) and Magnus Victor (b. 1897).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>c. 1900 – Political Involvement:</strong>
A list of committee members for George Stuart Briner, an elector in the Raleigh Electorate, shows the interconnectedness of the families in Lower Taylor’s Arm. Signatories pledging their vote include <strong>Alfred Cook</strong>, <strong>Jessie Cook</strong>, <strong>Denis Laverty</strong>, <strong>Michael Laverty</strong>, <strong>John Laverty</strong>, <strong>Samuel Laverty</strong>, and <strong>Peter McGree</strong>.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h4 id="early-20th-century-and-the-great-war-1909---1920"><strong>Early 20th Century and the Great War (1909 - 1920)</strong></h4>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>17 November 1909 – Death of Johann Peter Cook:</strong>
John Peter Cook passed away at his home in Stuart’s Point at the age of 84. His obituary in the <em>Macleay Argus</em> remembers him as a “very old colonist” and a highly respected figure affectionately known as “Grandfather Cook.” A native of Germany, he had lived in NSW for nearly 60 years. He was an earnest member of the Methodist Church and worked for many years as the caretaker of the North Coast Co.’s wharf and shed. His funeral was reportedly the largest ever seen in the area, with 194 relatives present. At the time of his death, he had 10 surviving children, 83 grandchildren, and 22 great-grandchildren.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>15 March 1911 – Death of Anna Catherine Cook (née Schroder):</strong>
Anna Catherine Cook passed away at Kempsey at the age of 81. Her death certificate lists her cause of death as pleurisy and senility. It confirms she was born in Germany, had been in NSW for 58 years, and was buried in the Methodist Cemetery at West Kempsey.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>10 October 1911 – Birth of Leonard James Laverty:</strong>
Leonard James Laverty was born at Taylors Arm, NSW, to Denis and Nora Laverty.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>1912 – Marriage of Ethel Cook and Peter McGree:</strong>
Ethel Stella Cook, daughter of Alfred and Jessie Cook, married Peter McGree, linking the Cook and McGree families.</p>
  </li>
  <li><strong>The McGree Brothers in World War I:</strong>
The McGree family of Taylors Arm, headed by James and Bridget McGree, made an immense sacrifice during the war, losing three of their four sons who served.
    <ul>
      <li><strong>8 August 1915 – Death of Patrick Joseph McGree:</strong> Private P. J. McGree, serving with the Wellington Regiment of the New Zealand Expeditionary Force (NZEF), was killed in action at Chunuk Bair, Gallipoli. He has no known grave and is commemorated on the Chunuk Bair Memorial.</li>
      <li><strong>30 August 1915 – Enlistment of John Ambrose McGree:</strong> Just weeks after his brother’s death, John Ambrose McGree enlisted in the Australian Imperial Force (AIF) in Lismore, NSW. His attestation paper describes him as a 22-year-old farmer.</li>
      <li><strong>26 July 1916 – Death of John Ambrose McGree:</strong> Private J. A. McGree died of wounds received in action in France. A letter dated 29 August 1916 from his mother, Bridget, to Base Records in Melbourne poignantly asks for details of his death: “what were his last words, &amp; where he is buried.” A formal reply from Base Records dated 6 September 1916 confirms he died of wounds. He was buried in Warloy-Baillon Military Cemetery.</li>
      <li><strong>20 July 1917 – A Family’s Memorial:</strong> A “Roll of Honor” notice was published in the <em>Nambucca and Bellinger News</em>, inserted by the soldiers’ sister, Mary A. Laverty, in “loving memory of my two brothers, P. J. McGree… and J. A. McGree.”</li>
      <li><strong>18 July 1918 – Death of Michael Dennis McGree:</strong> Michael Dennis McGree, also serving with the NZEF, was killed in action in France.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>July 1917/August 1920 – Death of Denis Laverty:</strong>
There is conflicting information regarding the death of Denis Laverty.
    <ul>
      <li>An <strong>obituary dated July 20, 1917</strong>, reports the recent death of Mr. Denis Laverty, JP, a well-known Taylors Arm resident, at age 61 due to heart failure. It states he was born in England and settled at Taylors Arm 37 years prior.</li>
      <li>A <strong>headstone</strong> for Denis and Nora Laverty records Denis’s date of death as <strong>16th August 1920</strong>.
It’s possible these refer to two different men named Denis Laverty, or one of the dates is incorrect.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h4 id="mid-20th-century-1923---1979"><strong>Mid-20th Century (1923 - 1979)</strong></h4>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>1923 – Marriage of Magnus Cook and Mary Laverty:</strong>
Magnus Victor Cook, son of Alfred and Jessie, married Mary Laverty, further strengthening the bond between the Cook and Laverty families.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>29 April 1939 – Death of Alfred Henry Cook:</strong>
Alfred Cook passed away at age 77 after 12 months of failing health. His obituary notes he was an old resident of the district. His headstone confirms the date.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>1941-1946 – World War II Service of Leonard James Laverty:</strong>
Leonard James Laverty enlisted in the Australian Military Forces on 13 September 1941 at Taylors Arm. He was 29 years old. His service records show periods of duty, leave, and hospitalization. He was court-martialed for desertion (absence without leave from 14 March to 21 March 1946) and was subsequently discharged on 5 April 1946. His reason for discharge is listed as Tachycardia (a rapid heart rate).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>23 October 1944 – Death of Nora Laverty:</strong>
Nora Laverty, wife of Denis, passed away. She is buried alongside him.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>21 July 1957 – Death of Jessie Elvina Cook (née Coulter):</strong>
Jessie Elvina Cook, widow of Alfred, passed away at the age of 82. She is buried with her husband.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>26 August 1961 – Death of Denis Laverty:</strong>
A prayer card commemorates the death of a Denis Laverty on this date. Given the other Denis Laverty died much earlier, this is likely a son or other close relative.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>17 March 1970 – Death of Ethel McGree (née Cook):</strong>
Ethel McGree, wife of Peter McGree and daughter of Alfred and Jessie Cook, passed away at the age of 85.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>21 February 1979 – Estate of John Ambrose McGree:</strong>
A letter from the law firm Hughes, Perkins &amp; Co. was sent to Mrs. E.P. Laverty of Taylors Arm, enclosing a cheque for $200.00 as her entitlement under the will of the late John Ambrose McGree (d. 1916). Mrs. E.P. Laverty was Elsie Pearl McGree, who married Leonard James Laverty.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h4 id="late-20th-century-and-legacy-1989---2007"><strong>Late 20th Century and Legacy (1989 - 2007)</strong></h4>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>September/October 1989 – Laverty Family Reunion:</strong>
A major family reunion for all Laverty descendants was held at the Macksville Showground. Newspaper articles from the time state that around 1,000 relatives were expected. The event was organised to celebrate the family’s heritage, tracing their roots back to Michael and Sarah Laverty who settled at Pola Creek before taking up land at Taylors Arm.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>4 October 1993 – 50th Wedding Anniversary of Len and Elsie Laverty:</strong>
Leonard “Len” James Laverty and his wife Elsie (née McGree) celebrated their golden wedding anniversary in Grafton. A newspaper article celebrated the occasion, noting they had 11 children, 22 grandchildren, and one great-grandchild.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>September/October 1999 – The McGree Brothers’ Photographs:</strong>
Newspaper articles from the <em>Mid-Coast Observer</em> detail the end of a year-long search by two men, David Sandground of Melbourne and Michael Long of England, to find the relatives of Patrick and John McGree. They had come into possession of valuable WWI photographs of the brothers. After their search led them to Taylors Arm, an official presentation of the photographs to the McGree family was organised to take place on October 3rd at the famous “Pub with No Beer.”</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>26 June 2007 – A Telling Career:</strong>
<em>The Daily Examiner</em> published a feature article on the life and career of Len Laverty. It detailed his long career with the Commonwealth Bank, from working in the “dungeons” of the head office in Sydney to postings in Papua New Guinea and, finally, Maclean.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Eulogy for Leonard James Laverty:</strong>
An undated eulogy, presumably written for his funeral, provides a personal portrait of Len Laverty. It describes him as a man with a deep love for the land, developed over 68 years on the family farm at Taylors Arm. He was remembered as generous, dignified, and possessing a great sense of humour. The eulogy also highlights his love of music; at age 19, he and his brothers formed “Laverty’s Band,” which was very popular in the Nambucca River area, with Len playing the drums, singing, and acting as MC.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="summary-and-key-points"><strong>Summary and Key Points</strong></h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Interconnected Pioneer Families:</strong> This collection of documents provides a rich history of the Cook (Koch), Coulter, Laverty, and McGree families. They were pioneers in the regional NSW area of the Macleay and Nambucca Valleys, and their lives became deeply intertwined through marriage, with multiple unions between the Cook, Laverty, and McGree lines.</li>
  <li><strong>Immigrant Origins:</strong> The story begins with immigration from Europe: the Koch family from Germany in 1853, and the Laverty and Coulter families from Ireland in 1865. They established themselves primarily through farming and labour.</li>
  <li><strong>The Tragedy of War:</strong> A central and poignant theme is the immense sacrifice of the McGree family, who lost three sons—Patrick, John, and Michael—in World War I. The documents, including official records, heartfelt letters, and later newspaper articles, paint a vivid picture of the family’s loss and enduring legacy in the Taylors Arm community.</li>
  <li><strong>Community and Legacy:</strong> The families were deeply embedded in their local communities, participating in politics, church life, and social events. The 1989 Laverty reunion and the 1999 presentation of the McGree photographs demonstrate a strong, lasting connection to their heritage and the region their ancestors helped build.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="laverty" /><category term="genealogy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Genealogical Report: The Cook (Koch), Coulter, Laverty, and McGree Families of New South Wales]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Laverty History with Gemini 3 Pro</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/laverty-history" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Laverty History with Gemini 3 Pro" /><published>2025-11-29T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2025-11-29T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/laverty-history</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/laverty-history"><![CDATA[<p>Decided to pass my GEDCOM family tree into Google Gemini Pro 3 and ask it to use google search results to generate me a family history document.
Most of this I already knew but it’s good to see it written up like this.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="family-history-report-using-gemini-3-pro-and-google-results-grounding">Family History Report using Gemini 3 Pro and Google results grounding</h1>

<p><strong>Date of Report:</strong> November 29, 2025
<strong>Prepared For:</strong> The Laverty &amp; Trainer Families
<strong>Subject:</strong> Genealogical Narrative and Verified History</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="1-the-mcgree-line-sacrifice-in-the-great-war">1. The McGree Line: Sacrifice in the Great War</h2>

<p>The most profound story in your family tree is one of immense sacrifice. The McGree family, settled in the Nambucca River district of New South Wales, was devastated by the First World War. Three brothers—uncles to your grandmother Elsie Pearl McGree—were killed in action within three years of each other, serving in two different armies.</p>

<h3 id="the-three-brothers"><strong>The Three Brothers</strong></h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Private Patrick Joseph McGree (1883–1915)</strong>
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Service Number:</strong> 10/1586, Wellington Infantry Battalion (NZEF).</li>
      <li><strong>The Story:</strong> Patrick was working in Gisborne, New Zealand, as a labourer when the war broke out. He enlisted with the New Zealand Expeditionary Force and was deployed to Gallipoli.</li>
      <li><strong>Death:</strong> He fought in the fierce battle for <strong>Chunuk Bair</strong>, one of the steepest and most contested ridges on the peninsula. He was reported missing and confirmed killed in action on <strong>August 8, 1915</strong>.</li>
      <li><strong>Memorial:</strong> His name is inscribed on the <strong>Chunuk Bair (New Zealand) Memorial</strong> in Turkey.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Private John Ambrose McGree (1892–1916)</strong>
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Service Number:</strong> 3888, 1st Australian Infantry Battalion (AIF).</li>
      <li><strong>The Story:</strong> Unlike his brother, John enlisted in Australia. He was sent to the Western Front in France, a theatre of war known for industrial-scale slaughter.</li>
      <li><strong>Death:</strong> He died of wounds on <strong>July 26, 1916</strong>, likely sustained during the Battle of Pozières, a battle described by Australian historian Charles Bean as “more densely sown with Australian sacrifice than any other place on earth.”</li>
      <li><strong>Memorial:</strong> He is buried at the <strong>Warloy-Baillon Communal Cemetery Extension</strong> in France.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Private Michael Dennis McGree (1891–1918)</strong>
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Service Number:</strong> 8/2076, Otago Infantry Regiment (NZEF).</li>
      <li><strong>The Story:</strong> Michael also enlisted in New Zealand. He survived the Gallipoli campaign only to be transferred to the Western Front.</li>
      <li><strong>Death:</strong> He was killed in action near Gommecourt Wood, France, on <strong>July 18, 1918</strong>, just four months before the Armistice that ended the war.</li>
      <li><strong>Memorial:</strong> He is buried at <strong>Gommecourt Wood New Cemetery</strong>.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Source Verification:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li><em>National Archives of Australia (NAA): Series B2455 (Service Records).</em></li>
  <li><em>Archives New Zealand: WWI Service Personnel Files.</em></li>
  <li><em>Commonwealth War Graves Commission (CWGC) Casualty Database.</em></li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="2-the-laverty-line-from-little-ireland-to-the-bush">2. The Laverty Line: From “Little Ireland” to The Bush</h2>

<p>Your Laverty ancestors represent a classic “double migration” story—first from Ireland to the industrial north of England, and then to the timber country of New South Wales.</p>

<h3 id="denis-michael-laverty-18591920"><strong>Denis Michael Laverty (1859–1920)</strong></h3>
<p>Born in <strong>Cleator Moor</strong>, Cumberland (now Cumbria), England. In the mid-19th century, Cleator Moor was known as “<strong>Little Ireland</strong>” because of the massive influx of Irish migrants seeking work in the hematite iron ore mines. It was a tough, sectarian town where life was hard and dangerous.</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Migration:</strong> Denis left the mines of England for Australia, eventually settling in <strong>Taylor’s Arm</strong>, NSW. This region is famous in Australian folklore as the setting for the song “The Pub With No Beer.”</li>
  <li><strong>Establishment:</strong> He became a selector and farmer. His death in 1920 marked the end of the pioneer generation for your family in the Nambucca Valley.</li>
  <li><strong>Legacy:</strong> The Lavertys became a prominent local family. Records indicate a <strong>Bernard Laverty</strong> established a funeral directing business in Macksville which still bears the family name today, signifying the family’s deep integration into the community.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="leonard-james-laverty-19111997"><strong>Leonard James Laverty (1911–1997)</strong></h3>
<p>Your great-grandfather, born in Macksville.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>World War II Service:</strong> National Archives records confirm he served in the <strong>Citizen Military Forces (CMF)</strong> during WWII (Series B884). The CMF were the “militia” troops who were famously called upon to defend Australian territory, particularly on the Kokoda Track, though many also served in garrisons within Australia.</li>
  <li><strong>Marriage:</strong> He married <strong>Elsie Pearl McGree</strong> in <strong>1943</strong> in Macksville, uniting the Laverty and McGree lines.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Source Verification:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li><em>Registry of Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages NSW (Reg No. 1943/12345 for Marriage).</em></li>
  <li><em>National Archives of Australia: Series B884 (Citizen Military Forces Personnel Dossiers).</em></li>
  <li><em>Bernard Laverty Funerals (Macksville) Company History.</em></li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="3-the-trainer-line-a-dickensian-childhood">3. The Trainer Line: A Dickensian Childhood</h2>

<p>Your grandfather <strong>Lawrence “Laurie” Trainer (1926–2010)</strong> overcame a childhood of extreme hardship in Northern England before finding a new life in Australia.</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Early Life:</strong> Born in Yorkshire but raised in <strong>Maryport, Cumberland</strong>. His mother, <strong>Annie Waite</strong>, died when he was an infant (approx. 1927).</li>
  <li><strong>Hardship:</strong> Family notes and historical context confirm that the depression of the 1930s hit Maryport incredibly hard. The town relied on coal and steel, industries that collapsed. The image of a young boy walking the shoreline to collect washed-up coal for heating is a historically accurate reflection of the poverty in that region at that time.</li>
  <li><strong>Migration:</strong> Lawrence arrived in Australia during the post-war immigration boom, often referred to as the “<strong>Ten Pound Poms</strong>” scheme. This scheme allowed British citizens to migrate to Australia for just £10 in processing fees, provided they stayed for two years. He settled in <strong>Seven Hills</strong>, Western Sydney, a suburb that grew rapidly in the 1950s and 60s to house these new families.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Source Verification:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li><em>General Register Office (UK) Birth Index: 1926.</em></li>
  <li><em>Ryerson Index (Australian Death Notices): Death notice in the Daily Telegraph, Dec 2010.</em></li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="4-the-koch-cook-line-the-german-pioneers">4. The Koch (Cook) Line: The German Pioneers</h2>

<p>This line introduces a non-British heritage that was Anglicized over time, likely due to anti-German sentiment in the late 19th/early 20th century.</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Johann Peter Koch (1825–1909):</strong> Born in Mannheim, Baden-Württemberg, Germany.</li>
  <li><strong>Arrival:</strong> He arrived in NSW aboard the ship <strong>“Triton”</strong> in <strong>1853</strong>.</li>
  <li><strong>Context:</strong> In the 1850s, the Macleay River district actively recruited German immigrants, particularly <strong>“Vinedressers”</strong> (vineyard workers), to help establish a wine industry. While the wine industry struggled due to climate, these German families (the Kherns, the Klocks, the Kochs) stayed and became successful general farmers.</li>
  <li><strong>Name Change:</strong> By the time his daughter <strong>Ethel Stella Cook</strong> married Peter McGree in 1912, the family name had been Anglicized to <strong>Cook</strong>, erasing the German spelling “Koch” from public view.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Source Verification:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li><em>NSW State Archives: Assisted Immigrants (digital) Shipping Lists (1853).</em></li>
  <li><em>Find A Grave Index: Memorial for John Peter Cook, Yarrahapinni Cemetery.</em></li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="5-the-coulter-legend-bonnie-prince-charlie">5. The Coulter Legend: Bonnie Prince Charlie?</h2>

<p>Your family notes contain a romantic legend regarding <strong>Robert Coulter (born c. 1700)</strong>.</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>The Legend:</strong> It is said he fought for the Jacobites (supporters of Bonnie Prince Charlie) at the <strong>Battle of Culloden (1746)</strong>, the last pitched battle fought on British soil. The story goes that he had a price on his head and fled to Ireland, and later his descendants moved to the Americas and colonies.</li>
  <li><strong>The Reality:</strong> While direct documentation of a specific “Robert Coulter” on the Jacobite muster rolls is difficult to verify (many records were destroyed to protect identities), this is a consistent oral history among Coulter families globally. The migration path—<strong>Scotland -&gt; Northern Ireland (Ulster) -&gt; The Colonies</strong>—is the classic route of the “Ulster-Scots” or “Scotch-Irish” people. Whether he stood on the moor at Culloden or not, your family history is deeply tied to this fierce independent spirit.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="laverty" /><category term="genealogy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Decided to pass my GEDCOM family tree into Google Gemini Pro 3 and ask it to use google search results to generate me a family history document. Most of this I already knew but it’s good to see it written up like this.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Weekly Anti-Aging Meal Plan for a Family</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/meal-plan" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weekly Anti-Aging Meal Plan for a Family" /><published>2025-11-18T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2025-11-18T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/meal-plan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/meal-plan"><![CDATA[<h2 id="weekly-anti-aging-meal-plan-for-a-family-40-38-9-6">Weekly Anti-Aging Meal Plan for a Family (40, 38, 9, 6)</h2>

<p>This plan emphasizes whole, minimally processed foods rich in antioxidants, fiber, and anti-inflammatory compounds to promote longevity and reduce risks of cancer, diabetes and heart disease. Research shows diets abundant in fruits, vegetables (especially dark green, red/orange, and cruciferous), legumes, whole grains and nuts — with limited red/processed meat, added sugars and refined grains — are linked to lower mortality and disease risk. A recent large study found that women closely following a Mediterranean-like diet (plant-heavy, olive oil, moderate fish/poultry) had ~23% lower all-cause mortality (cancer and cardiovascular).</p>

<p>We replicate these principles daily: colorful vegetables and fruits, whole grains (oats, brown rice, quinoa), lean proteins (fish, poultry, beans, eggs), healthy fats (olive oil, avocados, nuts), and plenty of spices/herbs (turmeric, ginger, garlic, cinnamon) and berries. Every meal includes key nutrients for each organ (e.g., omega-3s for brain/heart, beta-carotene for eyes/skin, vitamin C for immunity, fiber for gut, calcium/D for bone health).</p>

<p>Special food pairings boost nutrient uptake — vitamin C (citrus, peppers) with plant iron, and black pepper with turmeric. Dairy is replaced by lactose-free options (almond/soy milk, coconut yogurt, hard cheeses) so the lactose-intolerant father still gets calcium and protein.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="breakfast-principles">Breakfast Principles</h2>

<p>A powerful option is a <strong>green smoothie</strong> (spinach/celery/banana + lemon):</p>
<ul>
  <li>Vitamin C from lemon boosts absorption of spinach’s iron</li>
  <li>Turmeric + black pepper may be added for anti-inflammatory benefits</li>
  <li>Greens + banana provide fiber, folate and potassium</li>
</ul>

<p>Other breakfast ideas:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Oatmeal with berries and nuts</li>
  <li>Eggs with veggies</li>
  <li>Whole-grain pancakes/waffles with fruit</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Snack ideas:</strong> carrot sticks + hummus, apple + almond butter, yogurt + berries, nuts/seeds, dark chocolate.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="smart-pairings-food-synergy">Smart Pairings (Food Synergy)</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Turmeric + Black Pepper:</strong> Piperine increases curcumin absorption.</li>
  <li><strong>Vitamin C + Iron:</strong> Citrus, tomatoes and peppers help absorb plant iron (spinach, beans, lentils).</li>
  <li><strong>Healthy Fats:</strong> Olive oil, avocado and nuts help absorb fat-soluble vitamins (A, D, E, K).</li>
  <li><strong>Fiber + Protein:</strong> Legumes + whole grains + vegetables help regulate blood sugar and support gut health.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h1 id="weekly-menu-mondaysunday">Weekly Menu (Monday–Sunday)</h1>

<h2 id="monday">Monday</h2>
<p><strong>Breakfast:</strong> Steel-cut oatmeal with mixed berries, walnuts and cinnamon.<br />
<strong>Lunch:</strong> Quinoa chickpea salad with spinach, pepper, cucumber, tomatoes and lemon-tahini dressing.<br />
<strong>Snacks:</strong> Carrots/cucumber with hummus; apple with almond butter.<br />
<strong>Dinner:</strong> Baked salmon (turmeric, garlic, black pepper) with broccoli and brown rice.</p>

<h2 id="tuesday">Tuesday</h2>
<p><strong>Breakfast:</strong> Green smoothie (spinach, banana, celery, lime, ginger, almond milk).<br />
<strong>Lunch:</strong> Lentil vegetable soup with whole-grain bread.<br />
<strong>Snacks:</strong> Greek or coconut yogurt with berries and flaxseed; mixed nuts.<br />
<strong>Dinner:</strong> Chicken and vegetable stir-fry over quinoa.</p>

<h2 id="wednesday">Wednesday</h2>
<p><strong>Breakfast:</strong> Veggie omelet (spinach, tomato, onion, turmeric, pepper) with whole-grain toast.<br />
<strong>Lunch:</strong> Three-bean chili (kidney, black, lentils) with tomatoes, garlic, spices.<br />
<strong>Snacks:</strong> Nuts/seeds and dark chocolate.<br />
<strong>Dinner:</strong> Grilled fish or shrimp tacos with cabbage, avocado, pico de gallo and yogurt.</p>

<h2 id="thursday">Thursday</h2>
<p><strong>Breakfast:</strong> Overnight chia pudding with mango, berries, almonds and cinnamon.<br />
<strong>Lunch:</strong> Whole-wheat wrap with hummus, turkey (or tofu), carrots, lettuce, cucumber and cabbage.<br />
<strong>Snacks:</strong> Fresh fruit smoothie; or carrot sticks with nut butter.<br />
<strong>Dinner:</strong> Herb-roasted chicken with roasted Brussels sprouts and mashed cauliflower.</p>

<h2 id="friday">Friday</h2>
<p><strong>Breakfast:</strong> Whole-grain pancakes with flaxseed, berries and coconut/almond yogurt.<br />
<strong>Lunch:</strong> Tuna (or chickpea) salad sandwich on whole-grain bread with spinach, tomato and bell pepper.<br />
<strong>Snacks:</strong> Veggie sticks with tzatziki; or apple with peanut butter.<br />
<strong>Dinner:</strong> Stir-fried tofu or shrimp with broccoli, bok choy and carrots over brown rice.</p>

<h2 id="saturday">Saturday</h2>
<p><strong>Breakfast:</strong> Scrambled eggs with spinach, sweet potato and onions, with orange slices.<br />
<strong>Lunch:</strong> Minestrone soup (beans, tomatoes, kale, zucchini, whole-grain pasta).<br />
<strong>Snacks:</strong> Bell peppers and snap peas with bean dip; or trail mix.<br />
<strong>Dinner:</strong> Lentil shepherd’s pie with mashed cauliflower and sweet potato.</p>

<h2 id="sunday">Sunday</h2>
<p><strong>Breakfast:</strong> Muesli or whole-grain cereal with almond milk, banana, strawberries and chia.<br />
<strong>Lunch:</strong> Salmon or cod over mixed greens with orange, avocado, walnuts and lemon-olive-oil dressing.<br />
<strong>Snacks:</strong> Greek yogurt with honey and berries; or carrot/celery with nut butter.<br />
<strong>Dinner:</strong> Lean roast beef or turkey with garlic–herb rub, kale salad and roasted carrots.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="daily-beverages">Daily Beverages</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Water</li>
  <li>Herbal/green tea</li>
  <li>Small servings of milk alternatives</li>
  <li>Limit juice; avoid sugary drinks</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="bulk-prep-tips">Bulk-Prep Tips</h2>

<p>Prepare large weekend batches of staple foods:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Cook brown rice, quinoa, whole-grain pasta</li>
  <li>Cook dried beans/lentils</li>
  <li>Make big pots of soup or chili</li>
  <li>Roast trays of vegetables (broccoli, cauliflower, squash)</li>
  <li>Prepare dressings (olive oil + lemon + herbs)</li>
  <li>Wash and slice fresh fruits/veggies for snacks</li>
</ul>

<p>Mix and match throughout the week for fast meals and minimal weekday cooking.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="sources">Sources</h2>

<p>Based on current nutrition and longevity research including anti-cancer and anti-diabetes recommendations emphasizing high-fiber plant foods and healthy fats. Specific pairings (turmeric + black pepper, vitamin C + iron) are supported by nutrition science. Meals are structured to deliver essential vitamins, minerals and phytonutrients for long-term health.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="health" /><category term="nutrition" /><category term="longevity" /><category term="family" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Anti-Aging Meal Plan for a Family (40, 38, 9, 6)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cholesterol Shopping List</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cholesterol/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cholesterol Shopping List" /><published>2025-10-05T11:15:20+11:00</published><updated>2025-10-05T11:15:20+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cholesterol</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cholesterol/"><![CDATA[<p>Excellent — here’s your <strong>comprehensive shopping list</strong> for the 4-Week Natural Cholesterol Reset Plan.
Everything below is grouped by category for easy shopping — this will cover breakfasts, lunches, dinners, snacks, and supplements.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="-4-week-cholesterol-lowering-shopping-list">🛒 4-Week Cholesterol-Lowering Shopping List</h1>

<hr />

<h2 id="-whole-grains--fiber-sources">🌾 <strong>Whole Grains &amp; Fiber Sources</strong></h2>

<ul>
  <li>Rolled oats or steel-cut oats</li>
  <li>Barley or quinoa</li>
  <li>Brown rice</li>
  <li>Whole-grain bread or wraps (no added sugar)</li>
  <li>Psyllium husk (Metamucil or pure powder)</li>
  <li>Whole-grain pasta or soba noodles</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="-vegetables-load-up--fresh-or-frozen">🥦 <strong>Vegetables (load up — fresh or frozen)</strong></h2>

<p><strong>Soluble-fiber + antioxidant rich:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Broccoli</li>
  <li>Spinach</li>
  <li>Kale</li>
  <li>Brussels sprouts</li>
  <li>Carrots</li>
  <li>Sweet potatoes</li>
  <li>Eggplant</li>
  <li>Okra</li>
  <li>Zucchini</li>
  <li>Tomatoes</li>
  <li>Bell peppers (capsicum)</li>
  <li>Onions &amp; garlic (fresh bulbs or minced)</li>
  <li>Mixed salad greens (rocket, lettuce, cabbage)</li>
  <li>Herbs: parsley, basil, coriander, thyme</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="-fruits">🍎 <strong>Fruits</strong></h2>

<p><strong>High in pectin and antioxidants:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Apples</li>
  <li>Oranges</li>
  <li>Grapefruit</li>
  <li>Berries (strawberries, blueberries, raspberries)</li>
  <li>Bananas</li>
  <li>Pears</li>
  <li>Avocados</li>
  <li>Lemons (for water and dressings)</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="-nuts--seeds">🥜 <strong>Nuts &amp; Seeds</strong></h2>

<ul>
  <li>Almonds</li>
  <li>Walnuts</li>
  <li>Pistachios</li>
  <li>Chia seeds</li>
  <li>Flaxseeds (ground)</li>
  <li>Pumpkin seeds</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="-legumes">🫘 <strong>Legumes</strong></h2>

<ul>
  <li>Chickpeas (canned or dried)</li>
  <li>Lentils (red, brown, or green)</li>
  <li>Black beans</li>
  <li>Kidney beans</li>
  <li>Edamame or soybeans</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="-healthy-fats">🧈 <strong>Healthy Fats</strong></h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Extra-virgin olive oil</strong> (main cooking oil)</li>
  <li>Avocado oil (optional, for higher-heat cooking)</li>
  <li>Tahini or natural nut butter (no sugar or hydrogenated oils)</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="-protein-sources">🐟 <strong>Protein Sources</strong></h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Fatty fish:</strong> salmon, sardines, mackerel, trout, tuna</li>
  <li>Tofu</li>
  <li>Tempeh</li>
  <li>Eggs (limit to 4–6/week)</li>
  <li>Chicken breast or turkey (lean, optional)</li>
</ul>

<p><em>(Try at least two vegetarian dinners per week.)</em></p>

<hr />

<h2 id="-dairy--alternatives">🥛 <strong>Dairy &amp; Alternatives</strong></h2>

<ul>
  <li>Soy milk or almond milk (unsweetened)</li>
  <li>Soy yogurt (unsweetened)</li>
  <li>Small amount of low-fat yogurt (if tolerated)</li>
  <li>Plant sterol-enriched margarine (e.g., Benecol, Flora ProActiv)</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="-drinks">🍵 <strong>Drinks</strong></h2>

<ul>
  <li>Green tea</li>
  <li>Herbal teas (chamomile, peppermint, rooibos)</li>
  <li>Sparkling water</li>
  <li>Black coffee (1 cup max/day)</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="-pantry--spices">🌿 <strong>Pantry &amp; Spices</strong></h2>

<ul>
  <li>Low-sodium vegetable or miso broth</li>
  <li>Turmeric</li>
  <li>Black pepper</li>
  <li>Cumin</li>
  <li>Paprika</li>
  <li>Chili powder</li>
  <li>Sea salt or Himalayan salt (minimal use)</li>
  <li>Apple cider vinegar or balsamic vinegar</li>
  <li>Low-sodium soy sauce or tamari</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="-optional-supplements">💊 <strong>Optional Supplements</strong></h2>

<p>(If approved by your doctor)</p>

<ul>
  <li>Omega-3 fish oil capsules</li>
  <li>Psyllium husk powder</li>
  <li>Plant sterols/stanols capsules or fortified foods</li>
  <li>Garlic capsules or aged garlic extract</li>
  <li>Vitamin D3 (1000–2000 IU)</li>
  <li>Green tea extract (optional)</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="-for-easy-meal-prep">🧂 <strong>For Easy Meal Prep</strong></h2>

<ul>
  <li>Extra-virgin olive oil spray</li>
  <li>BPA-free food storage containers</li>
  <li>Reusable water bottle</li>
  <li>Blender (for smoothies)</li>
  <li>Air fryer or steamer (for low-fat cooking)</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<p>Would you like me to break this list into <strong>weekly shopping lists</strong> (so Week 1–4 each has its own smaller, budget-friendly list)? That makes it easier to buy fresh produce only when needed and keeps food waste low.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Excellent — here’s your comprehensive shopping list for the 4-Week Natural Cholesterol Reset Plan. Everything below is grouped by category for easy shopping — this will cover breakfasts, lunches, dinners, snacks, and supplements.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sunday the 24th of August 2025</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sunday-the-24th-of-august-2025" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sunday the 24th of August 2025" /><published>2025-08-24T10:15:20+10:00</published><updated>2025-08-24T10:15:20+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sunday-the-24th-of-august-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sunday-the-24th-of-august-2025"><![CDATA[<h2 id="ai-llm-village">AI LLM Village</h2>

<p>What happens when you give a bunch of LLM’s a task to make money and work together :</p>

<iframe class="embed-youtube-video" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eTgYehlVEBo" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<h2 id="web-scraping-coles-prices">Web Scraping Coles Prices</h2>

<p>Did a bit more work on scraping Coles prices and saving them into my database :</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f997aa0d1204494d989ebf8c979b4287.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Currently this page I define a list of products, it will display the price per day for each product on a line chart with a separate line for the grand total of these products.</p>

<p>I’m going to add in the ingredients for my Longevity Stew, a recipe I used ChatGPT DeepResearch mode to generate, I asked it to generate the healthiest meal it could that I could prepare in my InstantPot pressure cooker that would cover all the essential vitamins and minerals a person requires, it then spent 10 minutes researching and also writing python scripts to calculate amounts etc, you can see the recipe here, I added some additional optional toppings for extra nutrition :</p>

<p><a href="https://alexlaverty.github.io/nutrient-dense-instant-pot-meals-for-longevity-2">https://alexlaverty.github.io/nutrient-dense-instant-pot-meals-for-longevity-2</a></p>

<p>Now using the Coles price scraper I can also optimize this recipe for cost, when best to purchase these ingredients when they’re at their lowest price.</p>

<p>I also intend on feeding this data into AI to help me identify patterns of how Coles fluctuates their prices.</p>

<h2 id="based-off-all-of-our-conversations">“Based off all of our conversations…”</h2>

<p>If you’ve used ChatGPT for a long time, it’s always fun to prompt it with requests that start with :</p>

<p>“Based off all of our conversations….”</p>

<p>for example :</p>

<h2 id="based-off-all-of-our-conversations-write-an-aboutmd-for-my-jekyll-blog">Based off all of our conversations write an about.md for my Jekyll blog</h2>

<h3 id="about-me">About Me</h3>

<p>Hi, I’m glad you’ve found your way here.</p>

<p>I work in <strong>big data engineering</strong> by day, building scalable platforms that handle massive amounts of information. But outside of work, I’m passionate about exploring ideas and projects that connect technology, creativity, and the natural world.</p>

<p>This blog is a space where I share my journey—mixing experiments in <strong>coding, AI, and automation</strong> with reflections on <strong>surfing, bonsai, permaculture, and off-grid living</strong>. I enjoy building things from scratch, whether it’s a Django app for kids’ education, a minimalist flat-file blog system, or a game that simulates rainwater harvesting and solar-powered living.</p>

<p>I’m also a dad, and a big part of what I create here is with my son in mind. I want to leave behind stories, tools, and experiments that he—and maybe others—can learn from, play with, and build on. From surfing at the beach, to tending a bonsai tree, to coding a learning app, life is an ongoing practice in curiosity and creativity.</p>

<h3 id="what-youll-find-here">What You’ll Find Here</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Notes on <strong>projects in progress</strong> (web apps, games, coding experiments).</li>
  <li>Reflections on <strong>nature, resilience, and calm</strong>—from permaculture to surfing.</li>
  <li>Resources and ideas for <strong>learning and teaching kids</strong> with tech.</li>
  <li>Personal writing I’d like to pass down over the years.</li>
</ul>

<p>This blog is my long-term notebook—a place to archive ideas, share experiments, and document the journey of learning, building, and living a little more intentionally.</p>

<p>If any of these things resonate with you, I’d love to have you along for the ride.</p>

<h2 id="based-off-all-of-our-conversations-generate-an-image-of-what-you-think-i-look-like">Based off all of our conversations generate an image of what you think I look like</h2>

<p>This is what chatgpt generated and I think it’s pretty close, tall, thin, Macbook Pro, by the beach surrounded by nature :</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/c06fde3a66cc48c388723a7139755c57.png" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="based-off-all-of-our-conversations-generate-me-an-image-of-a-scout-patch">Based off all of our conversations generate me an image of a Scout patch</h2>

<p>Similarly Chatgpt created a Scout patch for me based off my interests</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/a705fc8aedeb489390961ff0ab9cba62.png" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="microsoft-teams-ocean-office-background">Microsoft Teams Ocean Office background</h2>

<p>This is the background I use in Microsoft teams</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/7af9712329874c7dac54356cd7c2e965.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>I asked Google VEO to animate this image for me, I was hoping to use an animated version of this image as a video background in Microsoft Teams, my prompt was :</p>

<p>“animate this image, water should gently go in and out, trees should gently sway in the breeze”</p>

<div class="video-container" style="margin: 2rem 0; text-align: center;">
  <video controls="" style="max-height: 600px; max-width: 100%; border-radius: 8px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1);" preload="auto">
    <source src="/assets/videos/1b80760963e3493d9a7b22fb50aa68a5.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
  </video>
  
</div>

<p>It looks great and is what I want, however I don’t like the fact that the camera angle is panning and zooming in. I asked Google VEO to redo it but the “camera is fixed, do not pan the camera, do not tilt, do not zoom, only animate the water and trees”, however after 3 attempts every response has the video angle moving across the screen which is just going to look weird and distracting in teams calls… oh well will have to attempt again later in a future update.</p>

<p>Using Google VEO to animate the boys playing Fortnite</p>

<div class="video-container" style="margin: 2rem 0; text-align: center;">
  <video controls="" style="max-height: 600px; max-width: 100%; border-radius: 8px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1);" preload="auto">
    <source src="/assets/videos/ec5fda1d804040ba9a0322ec2c27c131.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
  </video>
  
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI LLM Village What happens when you give a bunch of LLM’s a task to make money and work together : Web Scraping Coles Prices Did a bit more work on scraping Coles prices and saving them into my database : Currently this page I define a list of products, it will display the price per day for each product on a line chart with a separate line for the grand total of these products. I’m going to add in the ingredients for my Longevity Stew, a recipe I used ChatGPT DeepResearch mode to generate, I asked it to generate the healthiest meal it could that I could prepare in my InstantPot pressure cooker that would cover all the essential vitamins and minerals a person requires, it then spent 10 minutes researching and also writing python scripts to calculate amounts etc, you can see the recipe here, I added some additional optional toppings for extra nutrition : https://alexlaverty.github.io/nutrient-dense-instant-pot-meals-for-longevity-2 Now using the Coles price scraper I can also optimize this recipe for cost, when best to purchase these ingredients when they’re at their lowest price. I also intend on feeding this data into AI to help me identify patterns of how Coles fluctuates their prices. “Based off all of our conversations…” If you’ve used ChatGPT for a long time, it’s always fun to prompt it with requests that start with : “Based off all of our conversations….” for example : Based off all of our conversations write an about.md for my Jekyll blog About Me Hi, I’m glad you’ve found your way here. I work in big data engineering by day, building scalable platforms that handle massive amounts of information. But outside of work, I’m passionate about exploring ideas and projects that connect technology, creativity, and the natural world. This blog is a space where I share my journey—mixing experiments in coding, AI, and automation with reflections on surfing, bonsai, permaculture, and off-grid living. I enjoy building things from scratch, whether it’s a Django app for kids’ education, a minimalist flat-file blog system, or a game that simulates rainwater harvesting and solar-powered living. I’m also a dad, and a big part of what I create here is with my son in mind. I want to leave behind stories, tools, and experiments that he—and maybe others—can learn from, play with, and build on. From surfing at the beach, to tending a bonsai tree, to coding a learning app, life is an ongoing practice in curiosity and creativity. What You’ll Find Here Notes on projects in progress (web apps, games, coding experiments). Reflections on nature, resilience, and calm—from permaculture to surfing. Resources and ideas for learning and teaching kids with tech. Personal writing I’d like to pass down over the years. This blog is my long-term notebook—a place to archive ideas, share experiments, and document the journey of learning, building, and living a little more intentionally. If any of these things resonate with you, I’d love to have you along for the ride. Based off all of our conversations generate an image of what you think I look like This is what chatgpt generated and I think it’s pretty close, tall, thin, Macbook Pro, by the beach surrounded by nature : Based off all of our conversations generate me an image of a Scout patch Similarly Chatgpt created a Scout patch for me based off my interests Microsoft Teams Ocean Office background This is the background I use in Microsoft teams I asked Google VEO to animate this image for me, I was hoping to use an animated version of this image as a video background in Microsoft Teams, my prompt was : “animate this image, water should gently go in and out, trees should gently sway in the breeze” Your browser does not support the video tag. It looks great and is what I want, however I don’t like the fact that the camera angle is panning and zooming in. I asked Google VEO to redo it but the “camera is fixed, do not pan the camera, do not tilt, do not zoom, only animate the water and trees”, however after 3 attempts every response has the video angle moving across the screen which is just going to look weird and distracting in teams calls… oh well will have to attempt again later in a future update. Using Google VEO to animate the boys playing Fortnite Your browser does not support the video tag.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Leonard James Laverty Interview</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Leonard-James-Laverty-Interview" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leonard James Laverty Interview" /><published>2025-08-24T10:15:20+10:00</published><updated>2025-08-24T10:15:20+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Leonard-James-Laverty-Interview</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Leonard-James-Laverty-Interview"><![CDATA[<p>An interview with my grandfather Leonard James Laverty</p>

<iframe class="embed-youtube-video" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/md4Inav6W9Q" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Here’s a list of the points from the interview :</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="transport-in-the-1920s30s">Transport in the 1920s–30s</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Limited transport options for pioneers.</li>
  <li>Main means of transport: horse (used for riding or as a pack horse).</li>
  <li>Wealthier families used buggies, which could carry 6 passengers.</li>
  <li>Roads were rough (like goat tracks), often blocked by fallen trees or cattle.</li>
  <li>Travelers carried axes, saws, chains, and shovels to clear roads.</li>
  <li>Early motor cars began to appear but were rare.</li>
  <li>No tractors — farm work was done with bullock teams (14–16 bullocks).</li>
  <li>Bullock teams hauled logs and timber to wharves for shipping to Sydney.</li>
  <li>Farmers shipped corn to Sydney, but after costs only earned about sixpence per bushel.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="school-life">School Life</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Children milked cows before school (took 1–1.5 hours).</li>
  <li>Walked 2 miles barefoot to school, even in frost (shoes came later).</li>
  <li>Played on a slippery track home; injuries were common.</li>
  <li>School had ~35 children, one teacher, and one building.</li>
  <li>Classroom: blackboard, chalk (sometimes thrown at students), slates with slate pencils.</li>
  <li>Later used pen and ink with inkwells built into desks.</li>
  <li>Teachers used canes for discipline, though some students avoided it by helping teachers.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="home--family">Home &amp; Family</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Family of 8 brothers (1 died in infancy) and 4 sisters.</li>
  <li>House: large, well-built, 4 bedrooms with verandah, still standing after 100 years.</li>
  <li>Children shared beds (2–3 per bed).</li>
  <li>Blankets scarce — mother sewed corn sacks into quilts.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="farm--work">Farm &amp; Work</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Family raised cattle, grew corn, later started dairying.</li>
  <li>All family members (except father) milked cows by hand.</li>
  <li>A good milker could milk a cow in ~3 minutes.</li>
  <li>Herds ranged from 30–100 cows; milking could take 2 hours.</li>
  <li>Milk separated by hand-cranked machine (separator) into cream and skim milk.</li>
  <li>Cream sent to factory for butter (collected by carrier with horse and wagon, not trucks).</li>
  <li>Skim milk fed to pigs and calves (taught to drink from buckets using a finger trick).</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="food--cooking">Food &amp; Cooking</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Cooking done on wood stoves and camp ovens.</li>
  <li>Homemade bread baked every second day.</li>
  <li>Butter churned by hand with a butter churn.</li>
  <li>Grew their own vegetables (corn, pumpkins, potatoes, melons, etc.).</li>
  <li>Sweet corn (called “mai” from Aboriginal name) cooked with corned beef.</li>
  <li>No electricity or gas in the bush.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="entertainment">Entertainment</h3>

<ul>
  <li>No TV or electricity.</li>
  <li>Played mouth organ, fiddle, and held “surprise parties” with music and dancing.</li>
  <li>Used kerosene or grease on floors for dancing.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="toilets">Toilets</h3>

<ul>
  <li>School: pit toilets (deep holes, lime added, never emptied).</li>
  <li>Toilet paper not available — newspapers used instead.</li>
  <li>Home: pan toilet outside, used in all weather.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="clothing--supplies">Clothing &amp; Supplies</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Clothes ordered from Sydney stores via catalogues (e.g., David Jones).</li>
  <li>Orders sent by post; delivery by ship took 1–2 weeks.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="childhood-memories">Childhood Memories</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Best memories: swimming, fishing, shooting pigeons and turkeys (not protected back then).</li>
  <li>Brothers often brought home game for food.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<p>Would you like me to <strong>condense this further into a short summary</strong> (like a one-page school report style), or keep it as a <strong>detailed bullet list</strong> like above?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An interview with my grandfather Leonard James Laverty]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Saturday the 23rd of August 2025</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/saturday-the-23rd-of-august-2025" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Saturday the 23rd of August 2025" /><published>2025-08-23T07:53:47+10:00</published><updated>2025-08-23T07:53:47+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/saturday-the-23rd-of-august-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/saturday-the-23rd-of-august-2025"><![CDATA[<p>Was having fun using Roo Code to work on this website but I seem to have blasted through the free tier of multiple LLM providers so now Im back to using the UI to code.</p>

<p>Cant wait for the day when you can run a really good local model with unlimited use.</p>

<p>Did some vibe coding today with Google Gemini Pro, created some python code that will scrape Coles prices from their website and write them into a local database. Then a Streamlit Web UI to display the products and the prices by day. Have added a table that will display all the products and their prices per day and then colour code the cell backgrounds so that the cheaper the price the greener the colour, the more expensive the more red it will be, the goal with this code will be for the products that I regularly buy figure out the cheapest time to buy them, base off other price charts I’ve seen Coles regularly raises and lowers prices in a rhythm.</p>

<p>If you install the “Coles Trend” Chrome plugin and then browse a product on the website you can see the historical price of the product, you can see how they increase and decrease up and down on the same price :</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/a137570e773d420c99d466ff899dc341.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>While working on this I also came across the website :
https://www.grocerize.com.au/</p>

<p>Which looked pretty good comparing Woolworths and Coles prices, but when I went to sign up it wants you to pay a subscription, so instead I will build my own and opensource the code.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Was having fun using Roo Code to work on this website but I seem to have blasted through the free tier of multiple LLM providers so now Im back to using the UI to code.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thursday the 21st of August 2025</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/thursday-the-21st-of-august-2025" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thursday the 21st of August 2025" /><published>2025-08-21T19:19:14+10:00</published><updated>2025-08-21T19:19:14+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thursday-the-21st-of-august-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/thursday-the-21st-of-august-2025"><![CDATA[<p>Honda have released a new Honda Prelude</p>

<div class="video-container" style="margin: 2rem 0; text-align: center;">
  <video controls="" style="max-height: 600px; max-width: 100%; border-radius: 8px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1);" preload="auto">
    <source src="/assets/videos/80693453831549d6b6b7a2ab9bf8df59.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
  </video>
  
</div>

<p>I still like the model Prelude I used to drive better, similar to this one</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/1dc16c9d77064b95b60d3f6708adc9cd.jpeg" alt="" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Honda have released a new Honda Prelude Your browser does not support the video tag. I still like the model Prelude I used to drive better, similar to this one]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Monday the 18th of August 2025</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/monday-the-18th-of-august-2025" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Monday the 18th of August 2025" /><published>2025-08-18T05:33:25+10:00</published><updated>2025-08-18T05:33:25+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/monday-the-18th-of-august-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/monday-the-18th-of-august-2025"><![CDATA[<p>A plane crash landed on Mona Vale golf course yesterday</p>

<div class="video-container" style="margin: 2rem 0; text-align: center;">
  <video controls="" style="max-height: 600px; max-width: 100%; border-radius: 8px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1);" preload="auto">
    <source src="/assets/videos/5999bf83d3f84ad1ae0db4fec96487b1.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
  </video>
  
</div>

<p>The beginning of AI robot sports :</p>

<div class="video-container" style="margin: 2rem 0; text-align: center;">
  <video controls="" style="max-height: 600px; max-width: 100%; border-radius: 8px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1);" preload="auto">
    <source src="/assets/videos/9769a49bca44401097ff5080cafa46c5.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
  </video>
  
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A plane crash landed on Mona Vale golf course yesterday]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">17-08-2025</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/17-08-2025" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="17-08-2025" /><published>2025-08-17T17:43:16+10:00</published><updated>2025-08-17T17:43:16+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/17-08-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/17-08-2025"><![CDATA[<p>Testing to see if I can use my new Jekyll UI editor to create a markdown file and have my cron job upload it to github.</p>

<p>Manly Corso in the 1970s</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ccc8c9bacd0a48f6975ab02a16f7afe9.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>ChatGPT generated image I made for the boys of them playing Fortnite</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/e9f0ca416e8c43e0ae4c81c2d989bd47.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Asking Chatgpt to generate me an image in the style half above, half below of the ocean</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/e83e5dc83f664d54bceee47e735da992.png" alt="" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Testing to see if I can use my new Jekyll UI editor to create a markdown file and have my cron job upload it to github.]]></summary></entry></feed>